[theme music playing]
[Ria] Ma'am, I'm sorry,
but we aren't allowed
to accept any visitors at the moment.
We aren't your typical guests.
This is a courtesy call from the mayor.
[Emilia] And the former governor
of Poblacion Ardiente.
I need a huge sum of money
to get back into power
and stop my enemies' plans against me.
Like this one person.
I don't know if you're familiar with her.
Camia Cruz?
[Ivy] Doesn't ring a bell.
[Julio] The moment you got your own land,
you thought you could live
by your own rules.
Therefore, I'll make you feel
what it's like to own land
without the government's support.
-Where's my mother?
-Emilia had her killed.
[Diego] They killed my mother!
Where's the justice?!
-The Ardientes will kill you…
-Pandoy!
…if you go against them!
[Ivy] Mom, I agreed to do the procedure.
Just like what Dad said, learn to fight.
Learn to take risks.
And learn to have faith.
-Lily, my daughter.
-You remember me now.
You remember me!
Lily, I remember everything now.
I want to know what happened
after your father and I lost you.
I want to visit your father's grave.
Mom, for now, this ring will have to do
because I can't let you go back
to Poblacion Ardiente.
You and Mom will go
to our house in Manila.
What about you? Aren't you coming too?
I have to fulfill my promise to the people
of Poblacion Ardiente.
And I still have to seek justice
for my father's death.
[Diego] Please forgive me
for what I'm about to do.
I will never have peace
until I confront the people
who murdered my mother.
Sir Diego.
[tense music playing]
Stay alert.
Make sure you give this all to Papa.
And tell him that I still support him
despite what he did to me.
Don't forget to give him
all of that, okay?
Yes, ma'am.
You're such a good actress.
What are you doing here?
We kicked you out, right?
Tell me the truth.
Did you have my real mother killed?
[tense music playing]
Carlotta?
I'm worried about Lily.
Why isn't she coming with us?
What is my daughter planning to do?
Lily's house in Manila is really nice.
It has a peaceful garden too.
And if you get bored, the mall
is just 10 minutes away.
Carlotta, you're like a mother
to Lily too.
You know how I feel as her mother.
Please be honest with me. Woman to woman.
What is my daughter planning to do?
Camia, I treated Ivy--
I mean, Lily, like my own daughter.
And like you, I love her very
much. Even if we aren't related.
And as her foster mother,
I know that no matter what I do,
she will find a way to give her
family the justice they deserve.
-Thank you, Carlotta.
-No worries.
Thank you.
-How dare you?
-Did you have my mother killed?
Answer me. Answer me!
Honestly, I don't remember.
And, frankly, I don't care
if your mother died.
And, besides… You know? She deserves it.
Your mom was a slut.
-You murderer!
-Sir!
[screams] What are you going to do?!
-Sir Diego.
-Jepoy… Jepoy, let me go.
I can't let the governor get hurt.
[grunts]
Diego, stop it!
You're causing trouble again!
Stop it! Diego, enough! Guards! Guards!
[screams]
Get back!
Diego!
-[Emilia] Arnaldo!
-What are you doing?!
[Diego grunts]
-[Emilia] Stop it! Stop it!
-[grunting]
[Arnaldo] You bastard! I'll kill you!
[grunts]
[Arnaldo screams]
[grunting]
Sir Diego!
[Emilia] Diego!
[coughs]
Congressman, Diego's inside.
You ungrateful bastard!
This family raised you,
and this is how you repay us?!
[screams]
Arnaldo!
That's enough.
He started it!
Papa, he's accusing me
of killing his mother!
Why am I not surprised to hear that?
I'm glad to know that you have
some guts now, Diego.
But you're still an idiot.
Didn't it cross your mind
you could've gotten yourself
killed doing this?
Now listen.
Whatever it is you found out
about your mother…
you will keep quiet about it.
Do you understand?
Because I don't want
any insignificant matters
to add to my problems.
The best thing for you to do is
to apologize to your mother…
and to your brother
for the trouble you've caused.
You're a family of murderers.
You're all monsters!
[dramatic music playing]
Go ahead, Grandpa.
[tense music playing]
I'm not afraid to die.
I'm not afraid to die!
Do it!
Do it now!
[tense music playing]
[breathing heavily]
If you aren't afraid to die,
then I won't kill you just yet.
But I'll make you feel just
how much you deserve to suffer.
Take him outside!
[suspenseful music playing]
-Stop it!
-You bastard! You bastard!
You're all animals!
You'll pay. You'll all pay!
-Have they left yet?
-Not yet.
Miss Camia's over there.
Mom. What are you still doing here?
You'll get stuck in traffic.
Lily, I'm not going anywhere.
I won't live in Manila.
If you're going to fight the Ardientes…
then I won't let you go alone.
I'll fight with you.
Mom, who told you that?
Carlotta told me all about your
plans against the Ardientes.
-Nanny Carlotta!
-Lily… Dear!
Don't blame her.
She's only thinking of your safety.
Nanny Carlotta!
Lily, you can't force me
to change my mind.
If you want to exact revenge on
the Ardientes, I will help you.
[foreboding music playing]
Go ahead. Tie him up!
[foreboding music continues playing]
[groaning]
All right. Let's see how tough you are.
[vehicle engine turns over]
[Raul] Diego! Diego!
Diego-- Papa! Papa!
Papa!
-Now drive!
-Papa!
What are you doing to my son?
Papa! What are you doing to Diego?!
Papa, let him go!
Emilia! What are you doing?
Arnaldo, help your brother.
Papa, I'm begging you. Please.
I'll take his place!
Diego!
[grunts]
-Diego!
-Let him go!
[Raul] Diego!
-Raul!
-Let vermin chase vermin!
-Diego! Diego!
-[screaming]
-Raul!
-Why, Emilia?
You want to join your husband in hell?
-[Raul] Diego!
-I thought so.
-[Raul] Diego! Diego!
-[Diego screams]
-Diego!
[grunts]
Diego. Diego! Diego, son.
-[Diego groaning]
-Hold on. I'll get you free.
-Diego, son.
-[Diego wailing]
-Diego.
-[groaning]
-Dad…
-Animals!
Dad…
[Raul] Monsters!
I'm here. I'm sorry… I'm here for you.
I couldn't… I couldn't…
[dramatic music playing]
-I'm here now… I'm here now.
-[Diego wailing]
I won't change my mind.
You have to, Mom.
I'm your mother.
You can't just tell me
what I can and cannot do.
You don't know what you're
talking about, Mom.
You don't know what
the Ardientes are capable of!
Yes, I do. I know them inside out!
They killed my husband, your father.
They took advantage of me!
They tore our family apart.
If there's someone who'll get revenge,
it's me because I'm your mother.
I'm sorry, Mom. But I'll do it alone.
I don't want you to get hurt.
Lily, I'm sick of hiding.
I'm tired of being a ghost.
You don't know how much it hurts
not being able
to visit your father's grave
because you're hiding me away.
-Mom!
-Let me do this.
Let me fight for our family too.
Let me fight for you.
Let me give justice
to your father's death.
You're not the only one who lost someone.
I lost my husband.
I'm ready to face the Ardientes.
I'll make them pay.
Both of us, Lily, we'll both get revenge.
[tense music playing]
Mom.
[soft music playing]
[sighs]
This is hard for me, Mom. I can't?
I don't want to do this.
But for you, I will.
There's only one thing I ask of you.
All your decisions, everything
you do, has to go through me.
At all times, by any means,
you have to protect yourself.
Lily, I'm your mother.
I should be the one telling you this.
I know, Mom. I know you're my mother.
But there comes a time in every family…
when it's the kids' turn to look
after and protect our parents.
[sighs] Lily, you don't have to
take care of me.
I know, Mom.
But I love you so much.
I'm doing this because
I don't want to lose you.
I don't want to lose you again.
I can't, Mom.
[Raul] Loring!
Loring!
Hold on, son.
Just a bit more, Diego.
We're already here. Loring!
-Diego!
-Son.
-Diego.
What happened to Diego?!
What happened to him?
I knew this was going to happen!
-Son?
-What did you do to him?!
-Son!
-What did you do to Diego?!
-Son! Son, we're here.
-[Loring wails]
Why did you take your son home like this?
How could you let this
happen to your son?!
[Loring crying]
You're a useless father, Raul!
Diego. I'll come back for you, son.
I'll come back for you.
[Loring] Let go of Diego. Leave!
[wailing]
My informer told me the police
are monitoring
my gambling den in town.
Can't we do something
about this, Congressman?
Governor?
I'll talk to the police chief tomorrow.
And remind him that I line his pockets
with thousands every month.
Get him to control his people.
Okay.
Papa. You monster.
What did you do to my son?
Why did you do that to him?
And you, Arnaldo? Why didn't you stop him?
Why did you take my son and not me?!
Why?!
Are you scared of me? Are you a coward?
Let him go.
You're a coward--
-That's enough.
-Wait, Arnaldo. Don't--
That's enough.
Even your own son doesn't
respect you as a father.
Raul, do you know why you're still alive?
Because of my debt of gratitude
to your father.
If your father didn't save my life…
you would've died long ago.
That's why you should be careful, Raul.
All debts of gratitude have their limits.
Get him out of here.
[Emilia] Raul? What happened?
What happened?
[tense music playing]
I'm sorry if…
if I made you worry.
Forget that, Diego.
What's important is you're home.
I just couldn't accept
that my real mother is gone.
I didn't even get to know her.
[sniffles]
I want to find her parents. My relatives.
My biological relatives. Is that okay?
We'll help you find them, then.
Thank you.
-Have something to drink.
-Thank you.
Are you Rosa's son?
My grandson!
You have her eyes.
When you were still a baby,
she'd always read you books.
Your mother was intelligent,
always at the top of her class.
She had high hopes.
But she was a fool in love.
She went against an Ardiente.
[somber music playing]
We told her to leave your father.
But she loved him too much.
She didn't leave him until the very end.
Why did you stay silent?
Why didn't you do anything?
We knew what the Ardientes
were capable of.
We have loved ones to protect…
and we didn't want to end up
like your mother.
Take these. These are Rosa's things.
It will help us all heal.
That's Rosario. Your mother.
[somber music playing]
Mom, the Ardientes can't go
against me because they need me.
They need my money for their campaign.
Lily, you won't know for sure.
They're just using you.
[laughs]
-We're using each other, Mom.
-Each other?
Lily, I don't remember teaching you that!
Mom, I'm sorry.
It's just that the Ardientes
love to play dirty.
If you don't bare your fangs,
they'll eat you alive.
Ivy, do you want me to
contact Noel, Arthur, and Tonio?
Yes, please. As soon as possible.
We need them right away.
Lily.
Who are they?
[tense music playing]
I'm doing everything, Raul.
But why won't you still love me?
Camia… Camia…
[grunts]
Camia again?
Camia, is it?
Till now.
[door slams shut]
We need them, Mom. All three of them.
They're the ones who'll testify
against the Ardientes.
One of them is Arthur Dela Peña.
He used to work with Dad.
Do you remember him?
He's the one who saw
how Raul harassed you at school.
Let me go! Let me go!
[pot breaks]
He was also the one who Emilia
ordered to poison Dad.
That's the reason why Dad died.
And then we have Emmanuel Condez.
He worked as a gravedigger
for the Ardientes.
Raul ordered him to replace
your body with another one
to make us all believe you were dead.
And Antonio Vidal.
[tense music playing]
He was Emilia's former bodyguard.
He was the one who tried to kill you…
and buried you alive.
-Go on. Get out of here.
-Hey!
-Lily… Run!
-Get off me!
No! [grunts]
Lily, dear.
Mom. Don't worry.
You don't have to see them.
I'll take care of everything.
I'll talk to them alone.
No.
I want to see Tonio.
-Lily.
-But Mom…
I want to see the man who ruined my life.
-[Camia] Who are you?
-[Tonio] Don't be scared.
[Camia] Why? Don't come any closer.
We're going to have fun.
We'll play a game.
[Camia crying]
[Camia] No! Stay away from me! No!
[tense music playing]
Forgive me.
Please forgive me.
I'm sorry for what I did to you.
I'm so sorry. Forgive me.
[soft music playing]
Why did you do that to me?
I used to be one of
the Ardientes' most trusted men.
If you worked for them,
you were above the law.
I was drunk with power.
But not a single day passed by
that I wasn't tormented by my conscience.
I have a wife now.
And a daughter too.
I would die if what I did to you
happened to them.
Please forgive me.
[soft music playing]
May God have mercy on you.
[pensive music playing]
[Raul] You can't see her because…
your mother's gone. Emilia had her killed.
And besides… You know?
She deserves it. Your mom was a slut.
-You murderer!
-Sir!
[screams]
[Arnaldo] You ungrateful bastard!
This family raised you,
and this is how you repay us?!
-You're all animals!
-[Julio] Now, drive!
Ma'am?
It's fine. You may go now.
Diego.
What happened to you?
Ivy, you were right.
Everything you said
about the Ardientes is true.
What your parents and my father said.
What are you talking about?
Ivy, I'm not a real Ardiente.
I'm Raul's illegitimate son.
Emilia had my mother killed.
Like what she did to your parents.
I thought they would change.
But change isn't in their vocabulary.
Ivy, we have the same goal now.
And that's to destroy them.
Ivy, help me.
Come with me,
and let's take them to court.
Help you take them to court?
What if I told you, Diego,
that the right punishment
for the Ardientes
isn't written in the law?
So I'll take it into my own
hands and deal with them myself.
[tense music playing]
I'm sorry, my children.
We can't open the cooperative…
until you settle things
with Governor Alvarez.
But don't worry. I'm taking
measures to solve this problem.
But when will that happen?
Our food supply is running out.
The governor should return
what he stole from us.
That was from our blood, sweat, and tears.
Just have faith in me. Remember this.
A father never wants
to see his children suffer.
All I ask of you is
your understanding and patience.
I'll fix this.
But I also need your help.
Because I can't do this alone.
If you will help me, then I can help you.
[tense music playing]
Mister Fernan! Where are you going?
It's none of your business, Diego.
I'll go with you.
Ivy, the attorney's here.
-Good morning, Attorney.
-Good morning, Miss Aguas.
Meet my biological mother,
Miss Camia Cruz.
-Good morning, Attorney.
-Your mother?
It seems like we have a lot
to talk about, Miss Aguas.
Yes, we do. Join us for breakfast.
Well, if you want to put
the Ardientes behind bars,
you should tell me everything.
I want all the juicy details.
[tense music playing]
Attorney. The Ardientes have
so much influence and power.
How can we take them down?
They've gained power and influence
because their people defend them
with their lives.
Turn their people against them,
and they'll be powerless.
[Fernan] Stop right here.
[Diego] Mr. Fernan,
are you sure it's here?
Yes.
I'm sure the Ardientes are doing
some illegal activities here.
Come on, let's go.
Hey. Emilio.
Good evening! How are you?
I'm glad you could come visit.
-Mayor.
-Governor's here.
How are you?
Hey, Congressman. I'm glad you're here.
-Well, I had some spare time.
-Governor.
Business is doing great, isn't it?
-It really is.
-There are many players.
[quietly] Diego!
Mister Fernan, hang on.
Watch out for the guards.
Wait. Hold on.
Hang on! Careful. Someone's coming.
[suspenseful music playing]
Do you know them?
Those are Grandpa's men!
It looks like they're bringing money.
-Let's go check it out.
-Be careful.
How about our income?
-Olan?
-We're earning well.
-How well?
-Enough to retire if we want to.
-That's good to hear.
-Thank you.
Here he comes. Stay down.
[whispering] Hide. Go. Go. Let's go.
Let's go.
Hey! Where are you going?
Well? You're spying on us, aren't you?
-No!
-Really?
-No.
-No, sir.
All right. Come with me. Go on!
Come on!
[gunshot]
[tense music playing]
-Come on!
-Let's go, Mister Fernan!
Move it!
Hey. Find out what that was.
Sit down. Please, continue.
Don't mind that.
Someone must be celebrating his birthday
with a little too much fun.
Enjoy yourselves.
Please, continue. Keep playing.
[Fernan] Hurry! Hurry!
What happened here?
Hey!
Mister Fernan, let's go!
[Diego] Hurry!
-Go! Hurry!
-Go! Go! Hurry!
-Hurry up! Take cover! Duck!
-I knew it!
Congressman, we didn't catch them.
-How many were they?
-Two.
-Did you recognize any of them?
-No, sir. It was too dark.
I thought you sorted out
these problems, Governor.
Why are the police still spying on us?
It's impossible those were the police.
I spoke to the chief already.
If they weren't police,
then who were they?
Uh, Congressman,
I think we should stop
the operations just to be safe.
[scoffs]
What are you talking about, William?
Use your brain.
Think about it.
If we're going to close down
this gambling den,
what will those people think?
[Fernan] Diego and I saw the congressman.
He's running the gambling den
in this town.
We'll report them to the police.
What can the police do?
The congressman will just silence them.
The police are wrapped around my finger.
I control the information
that goes out to the media.
If there are spies out there…
I dare them to reveal themselves.
But Mister Fernan, what else can we do?
The Ardientes stole from us.
So, we aren't going to let them
get any money
from that gambling den.
We'll form a group.
We'll take back from the Ardientes
what's rightfully ours.
Let's see how tough they are.
Why did they even think
they could challenge us?
Mister Fernan.
Mister Fernan, don't do that.
You'll put everyone in danger!
I'm not forcing anyone.
Join me if you want to seek
revenge on the Ardientes.
And if you don't want to,
then stay out of this.
I'll join you, Mister Fernan.
-We'll join you.
-Thank you. Thank you.
-Me too, Mister Fernan.
-Me too. I'll join you.
-Thank you.
-Mister Fernan, I'll join you.
I agree with you. Diego?
[suspenseful music playing]
Let's go there.
[tense music playing]
Attorney, why are they here?
We're here to expose
the corruption, lies, crimes,
and mass murders committed
by Congressman Julio Ardiente,
his daughter,
former governor Emilia Torillo,
and her husband, Raul Torillo.
We have enough evidence and…
eyewitnesses to prove the crimes
the aforementioned people
have committed within
the decade they were in office.
Are they gonna be ousted…
-from power?
-Thank you very much.
[tense music playing]
I was Governor Emilia's former bodyguard.
She asked me to kill a lot
of people, including…
Camia Cruz.
She asked me to kill her out of jealousy.
[tense music playing]
I'm here to clear my conscience.
I witnessed how Mr. Raul Torillo
harassed Camia Cruz.
And also, how Emilia poisoned
Attorney Dante Cruz.
It's time for the people to know about
all the evil and monstrous deeds
the Ardientes have done.
This is to give justice to all the people
that have fallen victim
to them over the years.
Attorney, what can you say
to the Ardientes?
We're coming for all of you.
[dramatic music playing]
-No!
-Do you know those witnesses?
One of them claims
he was your former bodyguard.
They know a lot about you.
I already asked my staff
to track him, Auntie.
But my question is, who's behind this?
Your family has a lot of political rivals.
It might be another party,
a businessman you crossed, or…
Or what?
Camia Cruz.
Camia Cruz? Camia…
-Think about it.
-Camia.
Of all the things they could
accuse your family of,
they focused on Camia Cruz
and how you killed her husband.
If Camia Cruz were still alive,
she would most likely come for you.
[ominous music playing]
But what's bothering me is your
father's not doing anything.
Aren't we supposed to be
doing damage control?
Auntie, he probably hasn't
heard about this yet.
Julio's silence is unnerving.
You're the main suspect in this exposé.
Your father would most likely rat you out
just to save his ass.
So, you really have to know
what's going on, Emilia.
-Diego!
-Nimfa?
Diego! Diego, it's Dad. I heard him.
They're going to attack
the congressman's gambling den!
-What?
-Diego, I'm worried about Dad!
He might get himself killed.
Nimfa, listen to me.
No one else should know about this.
If the Ardientes find out
that Mister Fernan
is going against them,
your father's life will be at risk.
But don't worry. I'll go after them.
Come with me.
The three of you stay up here.
If someone comes, knock them out!
[suspenseful music playing]
Hey!
-Hurry, hurry.
-Where are you going?!
Drop your weapons!
-Go ahead and shoot!
-Drop your gun!
Hand me your gun. Hand it over.
[grunts]
Go, go! Keep an eye on him.
We'll leave them to you.
You got him, Dolfo.
[grunts]
[Fernan] Get down! Get down!
All of you, get down!
[suspenseful music playing]
Watch out!
-[unintelligible]
-[grunts]
Are you okay? Let's go!
Give me that! You!
Fill this up! Fill it up!
Don't move! Stay down! Hurry up!
Hey, stay down! I said stay down!
Let's go!
[suspenseful music playing]
[reporter] Is there any truth
to those accusations?
-You shameless thieves!
-Hey! Ouch!
Whoever's spreading rumors
about our family, face us!
That Camia Cruz is becoming
a problem. Is she even real?
She is real. She is a threat.
She's not the only one behind this.
Someone big is backing her up.
Who could that be?
Could it be her darned daughter?
Do you know whom I'm suspecting?
Miss Aguas.
It's time for me to fight them head-on.
If you want to face them, then I will too.
[theme music playing]